# DATA ANALYST

#### **GHIMIRE Suraj**

M.Sc. in Data Science, 3+ years of Data Analytics experience, analytical and well versed with Python, SQL, Power BI and Microsoft Excel. Good communication skills and teamwork. Available to start immediately. Open to relocation or remote job.

@ contact@surajghimire.com https://surajghimire.com **\ +33 6 34 90 53 37** 

**♀** Grenoble, France

in surajghimire03



## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Data Scientist, SIMAP laboratory, Grenoble INP Phelma

Mar 2021 - Sep 2021

- M2 Thesis Internship on Variable Selection of the Parrinello-Behler Descriptors for Neural-Network Potentials in Material Science.
- Modeled data with Linear, random forest and deep learning models .
- Used Tensorflow Keras, Feedforward (Artificial Neural Network in Deep learning) for feature selection. Machine learning Python Git

#### Data Analyst, Nazarene Compassionate Ministries Nepal

Mar 2017 - Aug 2018

♥ Kathmandu, Nepal

- Designed baseline and annual survey, data collection from the field, built a database, cleaned and analyzed data, project progress through indicators.
- Led a team of 10 as a Project manager for earthquake rehabilitation program.
- Communicated quarterly and annual reports/presentations to stakeholders of various programs undertaken by the organization.
- Coordinated with internal external stakeholders, budgeting and expenditure tracking, capacity building, logistics, procurement planning, assisting the program manager in other projects

Microsoft Excel | Power BI | Database | SQL | Project Management

#### Data Analyst, Qatar Power Construction WLL

## Feb 2016 - Feb 2017

Opha, Qatar

- Identified a business problem, created re-usable spreadsheet templates to cross check the attendance of site staffs.
- Maintained additional attendance database by imported from XML files to the spreadsheet template, Cleaned and rectified possible data entry errors using data validation and conditional formatting on Microsoft Excel.
- Reported and Communicated HR-related documents to the manager.
  Microsoft Excel VBA Database Data cleaning Leadership

### PROJECTS AND OTHER ACTIVITIES

- The Effect of dependence in selecting smoothing parameters in a Non-Parametric Regression mode (M1 internship).
   R Statistics
- Local Election of Nepal 2022 :- Web Scrapping of data, Pre-processing, Analyzing and Visualization. Python Power Bi Database
- COVID-19 Infection and Death Rate across the world:- Analysis and Vizualisation SQL Tableau
- Analyzing Job market Data in Power BI Power BI
- The Android App Market on Google Play Python
- Predicting Credit Card Approvals Python
- Analysis of General Election of Nepal 2017 as Election observer (under the supervison of European Union Election Observation Mission to Nepal): Data Collection, Pre-processing, Analysis, Vizualization Microsoft Excel

Presentation | Tableau

• Analyzed consumer behaviors (market research) in their use of transactions in predicting the market share of visa cards. Excel SPSS

### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science Industrial and Applied Mathematics (MSIAM)

Grenoble INP-Ensimag, Grenoble, France

m Sept 2019 - Aug 2021

- Machine learning, Analysis
- Mathematics, Optimization, Operation Research, Probability, Statistics, Model selection for learning
- Information retrieval, Data visualization

## **CERTIFICATION**

- Data Analyst with Power BI by Datacamp
- Data Analyst with Python by Datacamp
- Data Scientist with Python by Datacamp.

## **SKILLS**

Machine Learning Data Scrapping
Data Cleaning Data Validation
Visualization Data Analysis ETL
• Python Numpy Matplotlib Pandas
Seaborn Scikit learn
• Microsoft Platform Excel Power BI
Power Query DAX Report
Dashboard Microsoft Office
• Other language and tools SQL R C
Latex Jupyter VBA Git Spyder
Visual Studio
• Other BI Tools Tableau SPSS SEO
Other Skills
Social Media Writing
Soft skills Team Work Leadership

## **LANGUAGES**

• English, Hindi, Nepali

Proficient

French

Beginner

I hereby confirm all the informations provided here are true and correct. I updated my portfolio and project details on https://surajghimire.github.io.